arihantbooks.com 2014-06-25

# Privacy Policy | arihantbooks.com

**Visitors to arihantbooks.com:**

During any visit to the Arihant Publications India Ltd. website our server downloads the pages you wish to see along with something called a Cookie to your computer. Cookies enable a website owner to do handy things like find out whether the user has previously visited the site. This happens on a repeat visit by checking to see, and finding, the cookie deposited there on the previous visit. Cookies will not identify the user of a computer and can only record what areas of a site a computer has been used to visit. Anyone can set his or her computer so that cookies are not downloaded from the web site server, but most people are aware of cookies and do not block them out. If you object to Arihant Publications India Ltd. or anyone else, using cookies you should set your computer to block them.

**User Information**

Arihant Publications India Ltd. collects information on what pages are accessed or visited by consumers, as well as information volunteered by the consumer, such as survey information and/or site registrations. Arihant Publication India Ltd. uses this information for internal review, in order to improve the content of the Site and to notify consumers about updates to the Site.

Arihant Publications India Ltd. guarantees that if you supply your postal address on-line you will only be sent the information for which you provided your address but if you do not wish to receive e-mail from Arihant Publications India Ltd. in the future, or if you wish to be removed from mailing lists, please let us know by sending an e-mail or writing to 4557/15, Ramchhaya, Agarwal Road, Darya Ganj, New Delhi-110002 or [ info@arihantbooks.com. ](mailto:info@arihantbooks.com.)

Whenever you give us personal data, you are consenting to its collection and use in accordance with this privacy policy, including our use of cookies as explained below. 

**What personal information do we collect?**

We log your Internet Protocol (IP) address in order to receive and send information from and to you over the internet. 

When you register on our website, register for our newsletter, make an enquiry, submit material for inclusion on our website or enter a competition, you may be asked to provide some personal data such as your name, address, email address and interests. 

Bear in mind that if you include any personal data in any material you submit for inclusion on our website, it may be seen by anyone visiting this website anywhere in the world. Please do not submit any personal data that you do not want to be made public in this way, and please do not send us any personal data about anyone else without their permission.

We also automatically collect data about visitors to our website (for example on browsing patterns) by using cookies. We collect data relating to the routing, duration and time of communications (traffic data), such as records of the parts of our website you have visited, services you have used, and your location. We retain traffic data for three years. 

**To whom might we disclose your personal data?**

We may pass your personal data to anyone who needs those data in order to fulfill your requests for our goods and services, or to validate any payment details you give to us. Some of these people may be located outside India.

We may pass your personal data to our group or associated companies and to our data processors.

We may also provide your personal data to businesses (which may or may not be companies in our group) and who may use the data to send you information about other products or services. However, you may opt out of your personal data being used in this way when we collect your personal data. 

We may also provide your personal data to anyone who buys our business or business assets. Except as set out above, we will not disclose your personal information unless we are obliged to do so or allowed to do so by law, or where we need to do so in order to run our business (for instance where we outsource services or other people process data for us).

**What about "cookies"?**

"Cookies" are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. Our cookies do not contain any personally identifying information, but they will enable us to provide a personalized service and to store items in your shopping bag between visits. 

**Your consent**

By using our web site, you consent to the collection and use of this information by arihantbooks.com. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it. 

**Disclaimer**

Arihant Publications India Ltd. makes no warranties or representations of any kind concerning the accuracy or suitability of the information contained on this web site for any purpose. All such information is provided "as is" and with specific disclaimer of any warranties of merchantability, fitness for purpose, title and/or non-infringement. Arihant Publications India Ltd. makes no warranties or representations of any kind that the services provided by this web site will be uninterrupted, error-free or that the web site or the server that hosts the web site are free from viruses or other forms of harmful computer code. In no event shall Arihant Publications India Ltd., its employees or agents be liable for any direct, indirect or consequential damages resulting from the use of this web site. This exclusion and limitation only applies to the extent permitted by law and is without prejudice to any express provisions to the contrary in any written license or subscription agreement from Arihant Publications India Ltd. in respect of the use of any online service provided via this web site.
